Here in Malaysia, there is an almost overwhelming sense of euphoria,
馬來西亞這里一片歡欣
as the newly-elected prime minister
因為新總理
has given this impoverished nation the gift of hope,
給了這窮國一個希望
promising to raise the substandard minimum wage
承諾提高過低的工資
and end child labour once and for all.
并禁止使用童工
Already considered a living saint,
被譽為活圣人的總理
he has become this small country's greatest hope,
成了這個小國
for a thriving future in the new millennium.
新紀元的最大希望
Get closer, Jaco.
詹科  靠近一點
This is disgusting. How could you let this happen?
真討厭  你怎能讓這件事發生
I have negotiated my butt off, Giorgio.
我已經盡力商討了  佐治奧
I've tried bribes, I've tried gifts. I even sent him some pet oxen.
我試過行賄  送禮  甚至送寵物牛給他
I mean, they love that crap in Malaysia, but he won't budge.
他們喜歡的  但他不肯讓步
Listen, 50% of my inventory
聽著  有一半存貨
is manufactured in sweatshops on the Malaysian border.
都是在馬來西亞邊境做的
Something has got to be done.
要想想辦法
If Malaysia goes, what is next?
如果馬來西亞失敗  接著會怎樣
My entire panty line is made in Vietnam.
我的所有褲子生產線在越南
We'll all go bankrupt within a year.
我們會破產
The Malaysian must be eliminated, Mugatu.
一定要干掉那個馬來西亞人  莫加圖
What? No, I don't have time for this.
什么  我沒有時間做這件事
Perhaps you'd rather go back
你寧愿回頭
to turning out novelty neckties in Hackensack.
去哈肯薩克搞新奇領帶嗎
But my new fall line is almost due.
但我的秋季新系列快要面世了
And I trust you would like to live to see your spring line, as well?
你還想活著看你的春季系列吧
The Malaysian prime minister visits New York in 14 days.
馬國總理14天后來紐約
Do it then.
得下手
Fourteen days? That's Fashion Week. It's impossible! I have a show!
十四天后  那是時裝周  不可能  我有表演
It's perfect. Invite him to be your guest of honour.
好極了  邀請他做你的貴賓吧
That's not enough time. It takes months to train an operative.
沒有足夠時間聘請和訓練特工
What about Fabio?
費比奧如何
Too smart. This is a rush job. He's got to be extremely dim-witted.
太精明  是緊急任務  需要蠢人
-You know the profile, Jacobim. -A beautiful, self-absorbed,
-你知道要找哪一類  -一個漂亮  自戀
simpleton who can be manipulated and moulded like Jell-O.
能像果凍任意擺布的笨蛋
Or cookie dough.
或者像曲奇餅面團
-Or Play-Doh. -Any kind of dough.
-或泥膠  -任何種類的生面團
The point is, we need an empty vessel, a shallow, dumb, vacuous moron.
重點是  我們要個笨頭笨腦  無知的蠢人
And when he's finished, we'll dispose of him.
事成后我們會把他除掉
But who?
但找誰
I mean, where in all of God's green goodness,
我是說  去哪里
am I gonna find someone that beef-headed?
找這樣的蠢才
Derek, I just have a few more questions, if that's okay.
戴力  多問幾題  好嗎
Cool.
好的
So when did you know you wanted to be a model?
你幾時知道你想當模特兒
I guess it would have to be the first time I went through the second grade.
我猜第一次是我在二年級時吧
I caught my reflection in a spoon while I was eating my cereal,
吃麥片時  在匙里看見自己倒映
and I remember thinking, "Wow, you're ridiculously good-looking.
心想  "你真英俊
-"Maybe you could do that for a career." -Do what?
-可以當做職業" -做什么
-Be professionally good-looking. -Right.
-專業的英俊  -好吧
What would you say your trademark is, if you have one?
如果你有個商標  那會是什么
Well, I guess the look I'm best known for is Blue Steel.
我最著名的是藍鋼
What's that look like?
怎樣的
That's impressive.
很吸引
And then there's Ferrari and Le Tigre.
還有法拉利
Le Tigre's a lot softer. It's a bit more of a catalogue look.
老虎就較溫柔  是卡迪拉形象
-I use it for footwear sometimes. -Can I see that?
-有時用它來宣傳鞋  -可否看看
Look, without Derek Zoolander,
沒有戴力·祖蘭德
male modelling wouldn't be what it is today.
男模界就沒有今天
He is a fashion icon.
他是時裝界的翹楚
So, do you spend a lot of time working on these looks,
你是否花很多時間設計這些形象
thinking about them?
考慮它們
Sure. I've been working on Magnum for at least eight or nine years.
是  過去八  九年我在鉆研炮火
"Magnum"? That's intriguing. Can I see that?
"炮火"  很奇特呢  我能看看嗎
Are you kidding? I shouldn't even be talking about it.
你說笑嗎  我不該說出來
It's nowhere near ready.
還沒有準備好
It's almost like there's a light around him. He exudes beauty.
他周圍像發光似的  流露著美態
I think about Derek every time I design a collection.
我每次設計時裝系列都想起戴力
Derek, I don't know if you're familiar
戴力  你或聽過
with the belief that some aboriginal tribes hold.
始部族相信...
It's the concept that a photo might steal a part of your soul.
拍照時會把你部分靈魂攝走
What are your thoughts on that,
你靠被拍攝維生
as someone who gets his picture taken for a living?
對此有何想法
That Blue Steel look he does? Oh, my gosh! The style and the hair.
他做的藍鋼形象  天  那氣派和發型
You know, it's almost like the new afro for the white man,
就像白種非洲人一樣
but it's beautiful.
真是漂亮
Well, I guess I would have to answer your question with another question.
我要用另一個問題來回答你
How many "abo-digitals" do you see modelling?
你看過多少個土著做模特兒
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the fashion industry's biggest night,
女士們先生們  歡迎來到時尚產業最大的盛典
the VH 1 Fashion Awards.
VH1時裝頒獎禮
There he is, three-time Male Model of the Year,
他來了  三屆最佳男模
Derek Zoolander.
戴力·祖蘭德
He's like a muse.
他像在沉思
Proud owner of Blue Steel,
一鳴驚人的
the look that made him the legend he now is.
藍鋼形象始創者
He's almost too good-looking.
他實在太英俊了
Hey, Paco!
帕科
That would be my main deterrent in considering a relationship.
那是我考慮發展戀情的主要障礙
And that's who Derek Zoolander is defending his title against tonight.
他是今晚戴力·祖蘭德能否衛冕的對手
Hansel.
韓塞爾
-Hansel, right here! -All right, all right.
-韓塞爾  這里  -好了好了
The rookie sensation who has burned his way
令時裝界另眼相看
into the eye sockets of the fashion world,
和熱烈愛戴的
and left them clawing their faces for more.
新晉寵兒
Mugatu sucks! Support the prime minister!
莫加圖很討厭  支持總理
Mugatu uses slave labour!
莫加圖利用廉價勞工
Down with Mugatu !
扳倒莫加圖
You have to see something like that at an event like this.
在這種場合不得不見到點這種事
Ugly protesters bothering beautiful people.
丑陋的示威者騷擾漂亮的人們
There's no denying Jacobim Mugatu has used cheap Malaysian workers
詹科拜·莫加圖被告剝削馬來西亞工人
to make his, and most of the garment industry's, clothes.
制造成衣業大部分的衣服
-Derek! Derek! -Hey, Steve, how are you doing?
-戴力  戴力  -史蒂夫  你好嗎
You're going for your fourth straight Male Model of the Year award tonight.
今晚你要角逐第四次年度最佳男模大獎
Come on. Are you nervous?
緊張嗎
Well, there are couple of little butterflies in my basket,
我有點緊張
but I think I'm doing okay.
但我很好
We also hear you're working on a new look. Can you tell us about it?
聽說你有個新形象  能跟我們說說嗎
Actually, I can't, Steve, because it's not yet perfected.
事實上我不能  史蒂夫  因為它還沒達到完美
But I can tell you that it's called Magnum and...
不過我可以告訴你它叫做炮火
Shut, baby, shut!
閉嘴寶貝兒  閉嘴
If I tell you anything else, this guy's gonna kill me.
如果我再多說的話他會殺了我
Got that right. How are you doing, Steven?
沒錯  你怎么樣  史蒂夫
Maury Ballstein, Balls Models.
莫里·鮑爾斯坦  鮑氏模特公司
A man who needs no introduction.
一個無需介紹的人
Maury, you've handled every important male model for the last 30 years.
莫里  你掌管所有著名的男模三十年
-Derek's chances tonight? -Let me tell you something.
-戴力的機會多大  -我告訴你
Nobody can touch Derek. Nobody! I gotta get inside.
沒人能碰他  沒人  我得進去了
I'm shvitzing like a shmendrick with all these lights.
這些燈光令我冒汗
Derek! Derek! Are you worried about Hansel?
戴力  戴力  你擔心韓塞爾嗎
Not as much as I'm worried about Gretel.
不如擔心葛雷特
Hey, put that Hansel and Gretel line in your article.
把韓塞爾和葛雷特報導出來
I want people to know how funny I can be.
讓人知道我有多風趣
Oh, believe me, they'll know. It hits newsstands tomorrow.
相信我  他們會知道的  明天就會刊登
Excuse me, Mr. Mugatu. Mr. Mugatu, Matilda Jeffries.
抱歉  莫加圖先生  瑪蒂爾達·杰弗瑞
Time magazine.
時代雜志
Any comment on Prime Minister Hassan's wage increases
你對馬來西亞總理哈桑給制衣工人
-for Malaysian garment workers? -No, he has no comment.
-加薪有何意見  -他沒意見
Why don't you let him speak for himself?
你為什么不讓他自己說
Isn't it true you'd like to see the prime minister out of power
你是否真的想總理下臺
so you can continue exploiting cheap Malaysian workers?
讓你可以剝削馬來西亞的工人
Hey, Mugatu ! Screw you and your little dog, too!
莫加圖  你和你的小狗去死吧
Look out! She's got an egg !
小心  她拿了個雞蛋
Oh, my God ! Let go of me!
老天  放開我
Yes!
是啊
I just can't tell you how much this means to me,
我無法形容成為第一個獲獎人
to be the first recipient of this beautiful award.
對我來說意味著什么
We have a serious problem on our hands, Maury.
我們有大麻煩了  莫里
This Malaysian thing is getting out of hand.
馬來西亞的事正在失控
I hear you, Jaco.
我聽到了  詹科
What this, the Slashie, mean,
這個斜線  意味著
is you consider me the best actor slash model,
我是最佳演員模特
and not the other way around.
而不是倒過來
His proposed wage increase could ruin all of us.
這項加薪建議會害死我們
I need it taken care of soon. I have people to answer to.
我要辦妥它  我要向人家交代
All right, now to the important stuff.
好了  現在頒發大獎
These ain't no slashes, folks.
沒有兼職人士
These are the pure breeds.
全都是專業人士
Here are the nominees for Male Model of the Year.
獲得年度最佳男模提名的是
Young, hot, brash.
年輕  性感  炙手可熱
With more covers in his first year than any rookie model ever
比任何新晉模特拍更多封面
and an attitude that says, "Who cares? It's only fashion."
有著"誰在乎  時裝罷了"的態度
That Hansel's so hot right now.
那個韓塞爾現在很火
I hear a lot of words like "beauty" and "handsomeness"
我聽過很多諸如"漂亮"和"帥氣"
and "incredibly chiselled features."
還有"難以置信的輪廓分明"的形容
To me, that's like a vanity, a self-absorption,
對我來說  那些都是浮夸和自負
that I try to steer clear of.
而我設法擺脫它們
I dig the bungee. For me, it's just the way I live my life.
我蹦極  那對我來說僅是一種生活方式
I grip it and I rip it. I live it with a lot of flair.
我追求刺激的生活
I live it on the edge, where I gotta be.
我的生活充滿才能和刺激  那就是我
I wasn't like every other kid, who dreams about being an astronaut.
我不像別的孩子般夢想當太空人
I was always more interested in what bark was made out of on a tree.
我對樹皮的構造很感興趣
Richard Gere's a real hero of mine. Sting.
理查德·基爾是我的真正英雄
Sting would be another person who's a hero.
史汀是另一個英雄人物
The music that he's created over the years,
他這些年創作的音樂
I don't really listen to it,
我并沒怎么聽過
but the fact that he's making it, I respect that.
但事實是他在做這個  我敬重他
I care desperatety about what I do.
我很關注自己所做的事情
Do I know what product I'm selling? No. Do I know what I'm doing today? No.
我不知自己賣什么  做什么
But I'm here, and I'm gonna give it my best shot.
但我會全力以赴
Over the past decade,
過幾十年
male modelling has had a shadow cast over it by one man
男模界被一個人
and five syllables,
和五個字雄霸
Derek Zoolander.
戴力·祖蘭德
Modelling, to me, isn't just about being good-looking,
我認為模特不單要有副好面孔
or having a lot of fun and being really, really good-looking.
或經常玩樂和非常  非常好看
The calendar was great,
這月歷非常棒
because it gave people a chance to see a side of my versatility.
因為他給了人民機會看到我多才多藝的一面
The original Greek word for model means "misshapen ball of clay",
希臘語模特是一團泥土的意思
and I try to think about that every time I get in front of a camera.
我每次在攝影機前都那么想
Three-time Male Model of the Year.
三屆年度最佳男模
And the award goes to
今年獲得這項大獎的是
Hansel.
韓塞爾
Thank you, Lenny.
謝謝你  倫尼
You know, a lot of people said winning this award
你知道  很多人說
four years in a row couldn't happen.
不可能四度贏得這個獎
Well, I guess I showed...
我猜我證明了...
I think we've found our solution, Ballstein.
我想我們找到解決方法了  鮑爾斯坦
No, not Derek.
不  不要戴力
He's perfect, and you know it. Now make it happen.
他很適合  你知道的  做吧
It stings me like a fissure in my ass, but you're right.
這讓我不太舒服  不過你是對的
He's ready.
他準備好了
Who am I?
我是誰
I don't know.
我不知道
I guess I have a lot of things to ponder.
我有很多事情要思索
Hey, the results are in, amigo!
朋友  已成定局
What's left to ponder?
有什么好思索的
Nice comeback!
好一個卷土重來
I can't stand Hansel !
我受不了了韓塞爾了
I know, right?
我知道
Riding in on that scooter like he's so cool.
他威風地騎著那輛踏板車
-And the way Hansel combs his hair. -Or, like, doesn't.
-還有韓薩爾那個發型  -威風個屁
It's like, "'Ex-squeeze' me, but have you ever heard of styling gel?"
好像說"抱歉  聽過定型膠嗎"
I'm sure Hansel's heard of styling gel. He's a male model.
我肯定他聽過  他是個男模
Earth to Brint. I was making a joke.
地球呼叫布瑞特  我在說笑話
Earth to Meekus. Duh, okay? I knew that.
地球呼叫米卡思  我知道好嗎
Earth to Brint. I'm not so sure you did
地球呼叫布瑞特  我不確定你知道
'cause you were all, "Well, I'm sure he's heard of styling gel."
因為你一副"我肯定他聽過定型膠"的樣子
Like you didn't know it was a joke.
看起來你不知道這是個笑話
I knew it was a joke, Meekus. I just didn't get it right away.
我知道那是個笑話  米卡思  我只是沒立刻意識到
-Earth to Brint... -Would you guys stop it already!
-地球呼叫布瑞特... -你們能停下嗎
Did you ever think that maybe there's more to life
你們可有想過除了長得非常  非常
than being really, really, really, ridiculously good-looking?
非常可笑的好看之外  生命還有其他意義嗎
I mean, maybe we should be doing
我是說  也許我們
something more meaningful with our lives.
應該做點有意義的事
Like helping people.
比如幫助別人
Derek, what people?
戴力  什么人
I don't know. People who need help.
我不知道  需要幫助的人
Models help people. They make them feel good about themselves.
模特們幫助人們  他們讓人們自己感覺良好
They also show them how to dress cool,
還展示給他們
and wear their hair in interesting ways.
怎樣打扮和修飾頭發
I guess so.
我猜也是
You know what could really help you sort through these important issues?
知道怎樣解決這些重要問題嗎
What?
怎么
-Orange mocha frappuccino! -Orange mocha frappuccino!
-橙汁咖啡特飲  -橙汁咖啡特飲
Come on, man ! Come on !
來吧
"Derek Zoolander. A model idiot."
"戴力·祖蘭德  一個笨蛋模特"
-Brint! -Huh?
-布瑞特  -怎么
No!
不
Rufus, Brint and Meekus were like brothers to me.
雷佛  布瑞特和米卡思跟我情同兄弟
And when I say brother, I don't mean like an actual brother,
還有當我說兄弟時  并不是指真正的兄弟
but I mean it like the way black people use it,
我是指像黑人般的用語
which is more meaningful, I think.
是具有更深意義的  我想
If there's anything that this horrible tragedy can teach us,
這宗可怕的慘劇給我們一個教訓
it's that a male model's life is a precious, precious commodity.
就是男模特的生命是很寶貴的
Just because we have chiselled abs, and stunning features,
即使我們的腹肌鮮明  外表俊朗
it doesn't mean that
也會死于
we too can't not die in a freak gasoline fight accident.
可怕的汽油意外中
So today, ladies and gentlemen, I would like to take this opportunity,
所以  女士們先生們  我想藉此機會
to announce my...
宣布我的
Hansel. He's so hot right now. Hansel.
韓塞爾  現在這么厲害  韓塞爾
I would like to take this...
我想藉此機會...
People!
各位
I'd like to announce my retirement from the male modelling profession.
我想宣布退出男模界
What?
什么
I'm pretty sure there's a lot more to life
我很確定除了非常非常英俊
than being really, really good-looking.
生命還有其他東西
And I plan on finding out what that is. Thank you.
而我打算找尋出來  謝謝
Mr Mugatu ! Mr Mugatu !
莫加圖先生  莫加圖先生
If I could just have a moment of your time, please, sir.
可否打擾你一會
Just one minute of your time, please, sir!
只是一會兒  先生
Derek? Derek, hey!
戴力  戴力
What do you want?
你想怎么樣
Actually, I'm trying to talk to Mugatu,
事實上  我正在試圖跟莫加圖說上話
but he's tougher to get to than the president.
但比找總統還要困難
I thought you were gonna tell me what a bad "eugoogolizer" I am.
你想說我是差勁的"致悼遲者"
A what?
什么
A "eugoogolizer." One who speaks at funerals.
致悼遲者  就是在喪禮致詞的人
Or did you think I'd be too stupid to know what a "eugoogoly" was?
以為我蠢得不知道什么是悼遲嗎
How could you have written those terrible things about me?
你怎能把我寫得那么糟糕
Look, Derek, my editor put that headline on it, okay?
聽著  戴力  標題是編輯寫的
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I know it came off kind of harsh.
我很抱歉  抱歉  我知道這很刻薄
Yeah, well, fortunately for you, not too many people I know
幸好的是  我認識的人中
read your little Time magazine, or whatever it's called.
很少人看時代  或者隨便它叫什么
Look, maybe you could do me a favour.
或者你可以幫我一個忙
All I'm trying to do is get some background information on Mugatu.
我想找一些莫加圖的背景資料
Mugatu? If you knew anything,
莫加圖  如果知道的話
you'd know Mugatu's the one designer who's never hired me.
他是從不雇用我的設計師
Come on. There's gotta be...
行了  一定是...
Sorry, lady. Not interested.
抱歉  女士  沒興趣
Now, if you'll excuse me, I've got an after funeral party to attend.
現在  抱歉我要失陪了  我要出席喪禮后的聚會了
Go back home? You're overreacting.
回家  你反應過度了
I want to do something meaningful with my life, Maury.
我想做點有意義的事
I have deeper thoughts on my mind.
我有一些更深遠的構思
The other day, I was thinking about volunteering,
那天我在想關于志愿者的事
to help teach underprivileged children to learn how to read.
去教導貧苦兒童讀書
Just thinking about it was the most rewarding experience I've ever had.
覺得這是令我獲益良多的體驗
Derek, I don't think you're cut out for that kind of thing.
戴力  我不認為你適合這種事
I mean, maybe I could even have my own institute.
我是說  也許我甚至可以有自己的研究所
We could call it the Derek Zoolander Centre for Kids Who Can't Read Good.
我們可以叫它戴力·祖蘭德兒童讀書中心
What about us? We built this place together.
我們呢  我們一起建造了這地方
Look out! Tushy squeeze!
小心
Maury!
莫里
Derek, when I met you, you were a junior petite
戴力  我們剛認識時  你還是一個
who couldn't book a goddamn Sears catalogue,
連西爾斯目錄都看不懂的小孩兒
and who couldn't turn left to save his ass.
連左轉保護自己都不會
-Now look at you. -I can turn left!
-現在看看你  -我能左轉
Yeah, right.
是啊
Derek, please. Some male models go left at the end of a runway,
戴力  有些男模在天橋盡頭左轉
others go right.
有些右轉
You got a lot of gifts, but hanging a louie just isn't one of them.
你才華橫溢  卻不懂得轉左
Sit down !
坐下
Hey, you want to hear some great news?
想聽好消息嗎
Mugatu wants you for his new campaign.
莫加圖想找你宣傳新服裝
Didn't you hear me, Maury? I just retired.
你沒聽到嗎莫里  我剛退休了
But this is Mugatu, Derek.
但這是莫加圖  戴力
Right now, this guy is so hot,
他現在炙手可熱
he can take a crap, wrap it in tin foil, put a couple of fishhooks on it,
他抓起一件垃圾  放上幾個魚鉤
and sell it to Queen Elizabeth as earrings.
就能當作耳環賣給伊利莎白女皇
Derek, you're the laughing stock of the entire fashion world.
戴力  你成了時裝界的笑柄
What do we do when we fall off the horse?
我們墜馬時要怎么做
We get back on.
要重新上馬
Sorry, Maury. I'm not a gymnast.
對不起  莫里  我不是體操運動員
I'm going back home. I need to get in touch with my roots.
我要回鄉  我得找我的根
Figure out who I am. See you around, Maury.
思索我是誰  再見  莫里
Hey, Pop!
爸爸
It's me.
是我
Scrappy, Luke,
格比  洛克
you remember your brother, right?
記得你的兄弟嗎
What do you want?
你想怎么樣
I thought maybe I could work the mines with you guys.
我想跟你們一起在礦場工作
You know, all the Zoolander men together again,
祖蘭德家男人再聚首一堂
like when we were kids.
就像小時候那樣
Times have changed, boy.
今時不同往日
You wouldn't last one day down those coal pits.
你熬不過一天
Can't you even pretend to be happy to see me, Pop?
爸  你見到我就不能假裝高興嗎
Damn it, Derek, I'm a coal miner,
該死  戴力  我是礦工
not a professional film and television actor.
不是專業演員
Do us all a favour and get out of here.
幫我們一個忙離開這兒吧
Pop, wait, please!
爸  等等
Give me a chance.
給我個機會
I won't let you down. I promise.
我不會讓你失望的  我保證
Hold very still. Very still. I'm working right now. This...
別動  我在工作  這...
Oh, I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Did my pin get in the way of your ass?
我的針刺到你的屁股嗎
Do me a favour and lose five pounds immediately,
幫我個忙立刻減五磅
or get out of my building like now!
否則立刻滾出我的房子
Get out!
滾出去
I'm so tired ! No, Todd, not now!
我累透了  陶德  現在不行
It's Maury.
是莫里
Tell me something good.
說點好消息吧
You may have to start looking for someone else.
你可能要找別人
There is no one else. The show is in 10 days, Ballstein.
沒有別人了  十天后就要表演了  鮑爾斯坦
Jaco, I hear you, but the kid's mixed up.
詹科  我聽到了  但是這孩子很困惑
He went home. He's talking about going off to ponder
他回家了  他說要思考
and tutoring underprivileged retards or some shit.
和教育貧苦弱智兒或其他什么鬼東西
I don't care what it takes. Get him back.
無論代價如何  找他回來
We're running out of time. Capisce?
我們沒時間了  你了解嗎
Yeah, I capisce. Now if I could only ca-piss.
是的  我了解  我現在只想小解
My prostate's flaring up like a frickin' tiki torch.
我的前列腺脹得像個電筒
Give me a little pee-pee. Come on, a couple of drops.
讓我撒泡尿  兩  三滴吧
That's what I'm talking about!
我說的是這個
Surprise!
驚喜
What the hell's the matter with you?
你搞什么鬼
Pacheco back to pass.
馬高后傳
He's feeling pressure from Pressman.
他受到記者隊壓迫
He's tooking for his All-American John DeRosa, the wide receiver.
他正帶著他全美國的約翰·德羅薩  長傳接球手
He's got him wide open in the middle of the field.
他在中場乘虛而入
Big rush.
強勁的沖刺
Who's winning the match?
誰領先
Hits Kevin Connolly, the tight end down in there.
看緊凱文·康奈利  賽點在那兒了
State.
州隊
I think I'm getting the black lung, Pop.
爸  我想我患了煤肺病
lt's not very well ventilated down there.
礦洞里不是很通風
For Christ's sake, Derek, you've been down there one day.
天  你在下面只是一天
Talk to me in 30 years.
我做了三十年
Moisture is the essence of wetness,
水分是濕潤的要素
and wetness is the essence of beauty.
而濕潤是美顏的要素
Why'd you have to come back to this damn town?
你為何要回來這該死的小鎮
I wanted to make a new life for myself.
我想重過新生活
I'm sorry I was born with this perfect bone structure.
抱歉我天生骨骼完美
That my hair looks better done up with gel and mousse
頭發涂上定型膠和慕絲時
than hidden under a stupid hat with a light on it!
比用有燈的帽子遮住好看
All I ever wanted to do was make you proud of me, Pop.
我一直只想令你以我為榮
With what? Your male modelling?
做男模特
Prancing around in your underwear
穿著內衣到處跳動
with your wiener hanging out for everyone to see?
露出你那話兒讓所有人看見
You're dead to me, boy.
兒子  我已當你死了
You're more dead to me than your dead mother.
跟你去世的母親一樣
I just thank the Lord she didn't live to see her son as a mermaid.
感謝主她看不見兒子是條美人魚
Merman.
是美男魚
Merman !
美男魚
Who am I?
我是誰
Hello? Derek, you hearing me?
戴力  你聽到嗎
-God? -God?
-上帝  -上帝
What the shit are you talking about? It's me. Maury.
你在說什么  是我  莫里
I hope you're finished touching your roots,
你已經找到你的根了吧
because Mugatu's making you an offer you won't believe.
莫加圖給你提供了一個你難以相信的工作機會
You gotta get your tuches back here.
快回來
Well, to tell you the truth, I was a little hesitant at first, Mr Mugatu.
老實說  我當時有點懷疑  莫加圖先生
I mean, you've never hired me before, and I've been around for...
你從不雇用我  我也做了...
For ages and ages. You've been around for a long, long time.
很多年了  我從沒要求過你什么
I never wanted anything from you.
我從沒想從你這兒要任何東西
And now that you're retired, I can't have you.
現在你退休了  我卻不能找你
And it's funny how it switches like that.
這改變真有趣
But now the forbidden fruit must be tasted.
現在要嘗禁果了
Well, when Maury told me what you were willing to do, I...
當莫里告訴我你愿意時  我...
Todd !
陶德
Are you not aware that I get farty and bloated with a foamy latte?
你不知我喝奶會放屁和膨脹的嗎
My mistake, Jacobim.
我的錯  詹科拜
Your mistake, indeed !
確實是你的錯
Yes, Derek.
是的  戴力
What Maury said I was willing to do for you.
莫里說我愿意為你做的事
Let's get back to the reason that we're really here.
說回我們為何來這里的原因吧
Without much further ado, I give you
事不宜遲  我給你
the Derek Zoolander Centre for Kids Who Can't Read Good.
戴力·祖蘭德兒童讀書中心
What is this?
這是什么
A centre for ants?
螞蟻中心嗎
What?
什么
How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read,
兒童進不去大廈
if they can't even fit inside the building?
又怎能讀書
-Derek, it's just a small... -I don't want to hear your excuses!
-戴力  那只是個... -我不要聽借口
The centre has to be at least
這個中心至少要
three times bigger than this.
比這個大三倍
-He's absolutely right. -Thank you.
-他說得很對  -過獎
I have a vision.
我有一個抱負
And so do I. Let me show you mine.
我也有的  讓我給你看看
I can't help you, lady. I don't know nothing about Mugatu.
我幫不到你  我對莫加圖無所知
But you've represented every male model in each of his campaigns.
你代表所有男模
You must have some kind of a relationship with him.
一定認識他的
Even if I did, why would I talk to you?
即使我認識他  為何我要跟你說
Shame on you how you picked on Derek Zoolander in that story.
為何你挑剔戴力·祖蘭德
He's a sweet simpleton who never hurt a fly.
他沒有害人
Please don't change the subject, Mr Ballstein.
不要轉換話題  鮑爾斯坦先生
What about Mugatu's exploitation of sweatshop workers in Malaysia?
莫加圖剝削馬來西亞廉價勞工又如何
-Do you have an opinion on that? -You wanna hear an opinion?
-你對此有什么意見嗎  -你想聽意見
With a push-up bra, you could have a nice rack of lamb going on there.
魔術胸圍能讓身材豐滿
Let me show you the future of fashion.
我帶你看看時裝的前景
Let me show you
讓我給你看看
Derelicte!
頹廢
It is a fashion, a way of life,
一種受流浪漢  乞丐  妓女
inspired by the very homeless, the vagrants, the crack whores
啟發的時尚  生活方式
that make this wonderful city so unique.
令這城市變得獨特
And I want you, Derek, to be the face,
我想你成為頹廢的封面
the image, nay, the spirit of Derelicte!
形象  頹廢的精神
It'll be your glorious comeback.
形象會讓你輝煌地東山再起
Sounds cool.
聽來不錯
Derek, I'd like you to meet Katinka Ingabogovinanana.
戴力  我給你介紹卡廷卡·英格保格比娜娜
She'll be your day-to-day on the campaign.
她會負責你這次宣傳的日常事務
Let's get this model on his way!
我們改造這模特吧
The big show is in eight days, Derek.
大型匯演在八天后舉行  戴力
Like a caterpillar becomes a butterfly, so must you become Derelicte!
像毛毛蟲蛻變成蝴蝶一樣  你要變成頹廢
So you want me to sleep in the gutter?
你要我睡在貧民窟
No. We're sending you to a very exclusive day spa.
不  我們會送你去一間特別的療養院
So exclusive, no one knows about it. Our little secret, okay?
沒有人知道  是我們的秘密
-Matilda, hey. -Hey, Arch, what's up?
-瑪蒂爾達  -阿奇  什么是
Nothing. I've just been up for a few days,
沒什么  這些天我搜集了一些
putting together these background articles on Mugatu you asked for.
你要的莫加圖的背景資料
Wow! Very thorough, Archie. Thank you.
真細心  謝謝你
It's weird. I couldn't get any info on him before 1995.
奇怪的是  我找不到他在1995年以前的資料
It's like he just appeared out of the blue.
就像他是從天而降的
-Really? That's strange. -Yeah.
-真的嗎  這真奇怪  -是啊
-Matilda Jeffries. -Keep pulling the sweater.
-瑪蒂爾達·杰弗瑞  -繼續拉毛衣吧
-Excuse me? -Eventually the thing will unravel.
-什么  -整件事最終會弄清楚
You mean, if you pull the thread, the whole thing will unravel?
如果拉毛線  整件事就會弄清楚
Now you're talking, sister. If you want to know more, go to Pier 12.
現在你在說話了  想知更多就去12號碼頭
Things aren't what they seem.
情況并非像表面那樣
What kind of spa is this?
這是什么療養院
It's designed for deep, deep relaxation. Come, let's get you loosened up.
用作深層休息  你先放輕松
Good boy. Good boy.
好孩子  好孩子
Good boy.
好孩子
I'm sorry.
對不起
Derek?
戴力
Matilda, what are you doing here?
瑪蒂爾達  你來這里干什么
I was...
我在...
What are you doing here, Derek? I thought you quit the business.
你來這里干嗎  戴力  我以為你不干這行了
Haven't you heard? I'm the new face of Mugatu's Derelicte campaign.
你沒聽說嗎  我是莫加圖頹廢系列的新面孔
What do you mean, Derek? You said Mugatu never hires you.
你什么意思  戴力  你說莫加圖不會雇你的
Well, I guess he changed his mind.
是啊  我猜他改主意了
It's only the biggest campaign in the world. Ever.
是有史以來最大的宣傳
What is this? Who are you?
這是什么  你是誰
This is private property. Nils!
這是私人地方  尼斯
I suggest you and your Kmart Jaclyn Smith Collection outfit,
我提議你和你一身的廉價衣服
stay the hell away from Derek Zoolander.
離戴力·祖蘭德遠一點
How do you feel, Derek?
戴力  你覺得怎樣
Okay.
挺好
When's the seaweed wrap?
多久能弄完
You shut up now.
閉嘴
I want you to relax
我要你放松
and breathe deeply.
深呼吸
-I like this song. -Of course you do.
-我喜歡這首歌  -你當然喜歡
Hello, Derek.
戴力  你好
Hello.
你好
Welcome to your relaxation time.
歡迎來到你的放松時間
Let this wonderful '80s classic soothe you.
讓這首八十年代經典名曲舒緩你
Just a nice, warm, happy time.
舒適  溫暖  開心的時刻
Happy, happy, happy.
開心  開心  還是開心
Nothing to worry about at all.
什么也不用擔心
Just relax.
只要放松就好
Hey there, Derek. My name is Lit' Kteatus.
戴力  我的名字是小基提
I'm just a kid who wants you to know
我想你知道
the real truth about child labour laws.
兒童勞工法例的實情
-Okay? -Okay.
-好嗎  -好的
They're silly and outdated. In the good old days,
他們又笨又過時  在過去的好時候
kids as young as five could work as they pleased,
五歲小孩可以隨時工作
from textile factories to iron smelts.
從紡織廠到煉鐵廠都有
Yippee! Hooray!
耶  萬歲
But today, the age-old right of children to work is under attack.
但現在兒童工作權利受到攻擊
From the Philippines to Bangladesh, in China and India,
從菲律賓到孟加拉  中國  印度
and South America, too.
南美也有
But you can help these children, Derek,
但你可以幫助這些孩子  戴力
by killing the prime minister of Malaysia.
殺死馬來西亞的總理
-He is bad. -What?
-他是壞人  -什么
You learn martial arts.
你會學習武術
Prime minister of Malaysia bad!
馬來西亞總理  是壞人
Martial arts good!
武術  很好
Kill naughty man! Kill naughty man! Kill naughty man!
殺死頑皮的男人  殺死頑皮的男人  殺死頑皮的男人
Obey my dog!
服從我的狗
On the runway, you have one objective.
在天橋上你有一個目標
Do not be distracted by the beautiful cetebrities.
不要被漂亮的名人分心
Do as you've been trained to do and kill the Malaysian prime minister!
照受訓指示殺死馬來西亞總理
Karate chop! Bad, man! Awful man!
空手道  壞人
In your little blue suit and your spiky black hair. Kill!
討厭的人  你穿藍衣和梳黑短發  殺
You're a super-hot ninja machine!
你是超級強勁的忍者機器
-Derek, are you in there? -Hold your horses!
-戴力  你在嗎  -等等
-Derek, please open the door! -What a cuckoo dream.
-戴力  開門  -這個夢真傻
Derek!
戴力
-What? -Hey, are you okay?
-什么  -你還好嗎
I've been trying to reach you for a week.
我找了你一個星期
A week? What, are you having a whack attack?
一個星期  你瘋了嗎
I saw you this afternoon, dum-dum.
我今天下午見過你
That was last Friday.
是上周五
Earth to Matilda. I was at a day spa.
地球呼叫瑪蒂爾達  我在一個日間療養院
Day. D-A-I-Y-E. Okay?
日間  知道嗎
Look, I think I know what this is about,
我明白是什么一回事了
and I'm very complimented, but not interested.
我受寵若驚  但不感興趣
-What? -I can't sleep with you, okay?
-什么  -我不能跟你上床
-My head is killing me and... -What are you talking about?
-我的頭很痛  -你說什么
Okay, if you just want to fool around a little bit...
你想胡混
Hey, I don't want to sleep with you !
我不想跟你上床
I've been trying to tell you you've been missing for a week.
我試著告訴你你失蹤了一周
Would you look at the date.
看看日期
Mugatu's Derelicte show is tomorrow night.
莫加圖的頹廢表演就是明晚了
I don't care what the date says.
我不管是什么日期
You have 1,200 messages.
你有一千二百個口信
That is a bit above average.
稍微超出平常的數目
-Derek, what happened in that spa? -I don't know.
-戴力  療養院里發生了什么事  -我不知道
A little massage, some aromatherapy.
香薰按摩治療
I mean, look, lady, you can't just come barging into people's lofts,
你不能闖入人家的閣樓要求做愛
wanting sex, then changing your mind,
又改變主意
then telling them that they've been in a day spa for a week.
說他們在療養院一周
You have been in a day spa for a week.
你確在療養院一周
So what?
那又如何
Do you understand that the world does not revolve around you,
你明白世界不是在你四周轉動的嗎
and your "do whatever it takes, ruin as many people's lives,
你就不擇手段破壞別人的生活
"so long as you can make a name for yourself as a investigatory journalist,
讓你可以一舉成名當個調查記者
"no matter how many friends you lose,
不管失去多少朋友
"or people you leave dead and bloodied along the way,
或死了多少人
"just so long as you can make a name for yourself
讓你可以一舉成名
"as an investigatory journalist,
當個調查記者
"no matter how many friends you lose,
不管失去多少朋友
"or people you leave dead and bloodied and dying along the way"?
或死了多少人
Derek, I told you I was sorry about that article.
戴力  我對那篇文章感到抱歉
Enough! My head hurts!
夠了  我頭疼
And if it indeed is what day you claim it is,
若真是今天
I have a pre-runway party to attend, if you'll excuse me.
我要去表演前派對  失陪了
-By the way... -What?
-順便一提... -什么
With your complexion,
以你的樣子
you really shouldn't be wearing your hair pulled back that tight.
不該把頭發束起
What are you talking about?
你說什么
It pulls back the skin on your forehead,
額頭拉皮后
creating a tension which clogs the pores.
造成毛孔閉塞
That's why you have some light pattern dryness around your scalp.
所以你頭皮周圍有點干燥
Do you mind?
你介意嗎
Cool.
很好
l do not like snoopy reporter with lack of fashion sense.
我討厭缺乏時裝觸覺的史努比記者
Not one little bit.
一點也不喜歡
Hey, l just e-mailed you all those LexisNexis searches,
我剛發了電郵給你
on the male models who've appeared in Mugatu campaigns.
是關于做過莫加圖宣傳活動的男模
It's pretty weird. It seems like all of Mr Mugatu's models
很奇怪  看起來
have a bad habit of dying young in freak accidents.
莫加圖的模特都死于非命
What?
什么
-Wait a second. -What?
-等一等  -什么
-Oh, shit. I gotta go. -What's going on?
-該死  -我要走了
I don't want to hang out, okay?
我不想閑蕩  好嗎
I just need to speak with Derek Zoolander, please!
我只想跟戴力·祖蘭德談談
I just thought the way you handled losing that award to Hansel,
你的處理方式是令韓塞爾得獎
and then you sort of laid low for a while,
消聲匿跡一會兒
and then made your comeback...
再卷土重來
It was so courageous.
真是很有勇氣
Look, I gotta go pee,
我要去小解
but I'd really like to continue talking about this conversation
不過我很樂意繼續這個話題
when I come back.
等我回來
-Everything cool, Derek? -It's great, Biff. Thank you.
-一切都好嗎  戴力  -很好  謝謝
Hey, Derek. You rule.
戴力  你很棒
Thanks, Paris. I appreciate that.
謝謝  柏麗  我很感激
-Hey, Derek. -Hey, Maurice.
-戴力  -莫里斯
-Hey, my man. -What's happening?
-我的男士  -發生什么了
Derek, back on top, man.
戴力  東山再起
Thanks, Billy. You rock.
謝謝  比利  你很勁
No, you rock. When are you gonna drop Magnum on us, buddy?
你才勁  幾時推出炮火
Not yet. Gotta tame the beast before you let it out of its cage.
還不行  馴服猛獸后才讓它出籠
-Excuse me, bro. -You're excused.
-對不起  兄弟  -饒恕你了
And l'm not your bro.
我也不是你的兄弟
Whatever, dude. Whatever. Peace. God bless.
隨便吧  和平  天主保佑
Hey, Hansel, I'm sorry you didn't get Mugatu's Derelicte campaign.
韓塞爾  抱歉你做不到莫的頹廢宣傳
Maybe next time.
或者下次吧
What's that?
那是什么
Mugatu's Derelicte campaign. Sorry you didn't book it.
莫加圖的頹廢宣傳活動  抱歉你沒拿到它
Oh, yeah? I've never even heard of it.
是嗎  我從沒有聽過
Me and my friends have been too busy
我和我的朋友太忙了
bathing off the southern coast of St Barts,
去圣巴特南岸游泳
with spider monkeys for the past two weeks.
和蛛猴一起過了兩周
Tripping on acid changed our whole perspective on shit.
改變了我們的觀感
So l guess you can Dere-lick my balls, captain.
你可以滾蛋  隊長
Would you hold this for me?
你能拿著這個嗎
I can Dere-lick my own balls, thank you very much.
我可以滾蛋  謝謝你
You think you're too cool for school.
你以為自命不凡
But I got a news flash for you, Walter Cronkite.
但我有特別新聞報導
You aren't.
你不是
Who are you trying to get crazy with, ese?
你在跟誰發瘋
Don't you know I'm loco?
你不知道我是瘋的嗎
Hey, I got a wacky idea.
我有個怪主意
What say we settle this on the runway?
我們在天橋上解決這件事如何
Han-solo?
單挑
Stop it.
停
Are you challenging me to a walk-off
你向我挑戰
Boo-lander?
兄...蘭德
Don't do this, Derek.
別這么做  戴力
Listen to your friend Billy Zane.
聽你朋友比利·贊恩的話
He's a cool dude. He's trying to help you out.
他為人冷靜  他想幫你
Oh, yeah. That's a walk-off challenge, my friend.
是嗎  這是天橋比拼  朋友
Ten minutes. Old Members Only warehouse.
十分鐘  只限老會員貨倉
You oughta remember that. You're a dinosaur.
你該記得的  你是老人家
Let's go. Open up.
我們走吧  讓開
I heard some mad stories about this kid. He's limber. He's too limber.
我聽過他的一些瘋事  他很靈活
Put a cork in it, Zane!
閉嘴  贊恩
It's a walk-off. Walk-off.
這是天橋比拼
This is urgent, ma'am. Do you have any...
這是急事  你有沒有...
Derek? Derek! Derek!
戴力  戴力  戴力
Hey, Matilda.
瑪蒂爾達
What is this? Where is everyone going?
這是什么  大家要去哪
Good luck, Derek! Kick Hansel's ass!
祝好運  戴力  揍扁韓塞爾
Thanks, Rico. I'll try.
謝謝  我會的
You want to see the real world of male modelling?
你想看看男模的真實世界嗎
The one they don't show you in magazines or the E! channel?
雜志和娛樂頻道沒有介紹的東西
Yeah, I guess. Derek, please.
好的  戴力  請
I have something really important to talk to you about.
我有要事跟你談
Not now, Matilda.
不是現在  瑪蒂爾達
Han-sell-out is about to have his Han-sell-ass
現在不行  韓塞爾準備
handed to him on a platter with french-fried potatoes.
讓他的屁股給打得落花流水
Katinka, thought you might want to know,
卡廷卡  你可能想知道
your boy Zoolander's rolling.
你的祖蘭德要走了
It's a walk-off.
是天橋比拼
All right, who's gonna call this sucker?
誰來召集這個混蛋
If nobody has any objections,
如果沒有異議
I believe I might be of service.
我可以效勞
Now, this'll be a straight walk-off, old school rules.
這是一次直接比拼  學校老規矩
First model walks, second model duplicates,
第一個先行  第二個模仿
then elaborates.
然后發揮
Okay, boys, let's go to work.
好  我們來吧
Age before beauty, goat cheese.
年齡比相貌重要
Whatever.
隨便吧
Right.
好
Playschool, baby.
小兒科
You got to cut me. I can't see. I'm blind out there.
你要幫我修剪  我看不見東西
Evian. Evian.
礦泉水
It's okay. It's okay.
沒事
-Where am I? Where am I? -It's okay.
-我在哪  -沒事了
-Kickin', Hoss. -I'm going monk.
-放松點  -我要做修道士
I got to go monk. Prayer. Prayer.
我要做修道士  祈禱
Pray to the Great Spirit.
向神靈祈禱
Do it, Hansel. Just do it. Do it, Hansel.
放手做吧  韓塞爾  做吧
Why is he sticking his hand in his pants?
為何他把手插入褲里
Do it, Hansel.
來吧  韓塞爾
That's what I'm talking about.
我說什么來著
Derek, you're not a kid any more. You could hurt yourself out there.
戴力  你不是小孩了  你會弄傷自己的
I can do this, Tyson.
我做得來的  泰森
Thank God I wore underwear today.
幸好我今天穿了內褲
He's going for it.
他要來了
Oh, my God.
我的上帝
Disqualified.
取消資格
Derek, come on. Come on.
戴力  走吧  來
Come on.
來吧
What's going on?
什么事
I think Katinka wants to kill you.
我想卡廷卡想殺了你
Good. I deserve to die if I can't beat Han-suck-ass in a walk-off.
好  我打不贏韓塞爾是死有余辜
Derek, that's not true.
戴力  那不是真的
The guy had to miraculously pull his underwear out of his butt
他要抽出內褲
just to beat you.
只是想擊敗你
And all he had to do was turn left.
他只需轉左就行了
What do you mean?
什么意思
I'm not an ambi-turner.
我不能兩面轉
It's a problem I had since I was a baby.
自小就有這問題
I can't turn left.
我不能向左轉
Derek, that's nothing to be ashamed of.
戴力  這么什么好丟人的
I'm sure there are a lot of people out there who can't turn...
我肯定有很多人都不能轉
I mean, there have got to be some people out there,
我是說  一定有一些人
just like you, who can't turn...
像你那樣不能轉...
Turn left.
向左轉
Hello.
喂
If you want answers, come to Saint Adonis Cemetery now.
你想要答案現在就來圣安東墳場
Wait! Wait! Wait! Who are you?
等一等  你是誰
Who was that?
是誰
I'm not sure. I have to get to Saint Adonis Cemetery.
我不知道  我要去圣安東墳場
Listen, I'm gonna take you to my apartment, okay?
聽著  我要帶你回我公寓
You can stay there until I get back.
你可以在那呆著等我回來
Can I come with?
我能一起去嗎
I don't want to be alone tonight.
我今晚不想自己一人
Pedro Scialfa.
佩德羅·斯爾法
He died when he was 29.
他二十九歲時死了
Vin Correjo.
文·克里歐
"Derriere Extraordinaire."
"美臀"
92 minus 63.
92減63
None of them ever made it past 30.
他們都活不過三十歲
I did.
我活過了
Who are you?
你是誰
It's not important.
這不重要
Are you a ghost?
你是不是鬼
He called, Derek.
是他打電話來的
Let's take a walk.
我們去散步吧
You think Zoolander's in trouble? Think again.
你以為祖蘭德有麻煩  想清楚吧
What you've stumbled upon goes way deeper than you could ever fathom.
你碰著的事比你能理解的深奧
The fashion industry has been behind,
兩百年來時裝界在背后
every major political assassination over the last 200 years.
一直進行著主要的政治暗殺
And behind every hit, a card-carrying male model.
每次下手都有一個典型的男模
Okay, that's impossible.
那不可能
Oh, yeah? Listen and learn, sweetness.
是嗎  好好聽著  甜心
Abe Lincoln wanted to abolish slavery, right?
林肯想要廢除奴隸制  對嗎
But who do you think made the powdered wigs
早期領袖們的假發
and coloured leg stockings, worn by our country's early leaders?
和褲是誰做的
Mugatu!
莫加圖
Slaves, Derek.
是奴隸  戴力
Without their free labour, prices on such items would have gone up tenfold.
沒免費勞工  這些產品要貴十倍
So the powers that be hired John Wilkes Booth,
所以要雇用約翰·威爾克斯·布斯
the originat model/actor, to do Mr Lincoln in.
那模特兒兼演員  殺林肯的兇手
I'll go on.
我會繼續說
Dallas, Texas, 1963.
1963年德克薩斯州達拉斯市
Kennedy had just put a trade embargo on Cuba,
甘尼迪對古巴實施貿易限制
ostensibly halting the shipment of Cuban-manufactured slacks.
扣留一批當時流行的
Incredibly popular item at the time.
古巴制長褲
Lee Harvey Oswald was not a male model.
李·哈維·奧斯瓦爾德不是個男模
You're God damn right he wasn't.
完全正確  他不是
But those two lookers who capped Kennedy
但兩個阻止他
from the grassy knoll sure as shit were.
去綠茵墩的路人是
Well, what about you?
那你呢
How do you fit in to all this?
你跟這件事又有何關聯
This nation was swept...
這個國家充斥著...
I'll get it, ma'am.
我來撿吧
I can't get over...
我不能...
Wait a minute.
等等
-No. -I know that hand.
-不  -我知道這只手
It was in the fall 1973 Bulova watch catalogue.
它在1973年寶路華表目錄出現過
You're J. P. Prewitt.
你是J.P.普魯伊特
The world's greatest hand model.
世界上最好的手模
Once upon a time. But things change.
曾經是  但情況改變了
Thanks to this homemade hyperbaric chamber,
幸好這自制高壓罩
my sweet baby never did.
保住我的寶貝
Let's keep moving.
我們繼續吧
And that's when I found out I was in line to assassinate Jimmy Carter.
后來我發覺我要行刺吉米·卡特
-So, how did you manage to escape? -Because I'm a hand model, mama.
-所以  你怎么能逃走  -因為我是手模
A finger jockey. We don't think the same way
一個手指騎師  不像不像以面孔和身體的
as the face and body boys do.
男模那樣思考
-We're a different breed. -So why male models?
-我們不一樣  -所以為什么是男模
Think about it, Derek.
想想吧  戴力
Male models are genetically constructed to become assassins.
男模是天生當殺手的好材料
They're in peak physical condition.
他們的體格處于顛峰狀態
They can gain entry to the most secure places in the world.
可以進入保安最嚴密的地方
And most important of all, models don't think for themselves.
最重要的是  模特不顧及自己
-They do as they're told. -That is not true.
-他們依指示行事  -不是的
-Yes, it is, Derek. -Okay.
-是的  戴力  -好吧
Yeah. Think about any photo shoot you've ever been on.
想想你拍過的照片
You're a monkey, Derek! You're a monkey.
你是只猴子  戴力  你是只猴子
Dance, monkey, in your little spangly shoes!
穿著光亮的鞋跳舞
Mash your cymbals, chimpy! Dance, Derek, dance!
敲打你的鈸吧  跳舞
Good point.
有道理
But if this has been going on for so long, Mugatu...
若這種事進行了這么久  莫加圖...
He's just a punk-ass errand boy,
他只是個跑腿小流氓
working for an international syndicate of fashion designers.
為一個國際時裝設計師集團工作
You do a little background check on your Mr Mugatu.
你調查一下莫加圖的背景吧
You'll find that he sold his soul to the devil for a shot at the big time.
你會發現他為了圖利而出賣靈魂給魔鬼
But why male models?
但是為什么是男模
Are you serious? I just... l just told you that a moment ago.
你是認真的嗎  我剛才告訴你了
Right.
是啊
You're a killing machine, Derek. They've programmed you.
你是部殺人機器  戴力  他們控制了你
But I won't do it. I won't kill anybody.
但是我不會做的  我不會殺任何人
It's not up to you.
由不得你做不做
At the proper moment, they'll trigger you,
在適當時候他們會觸發你行動
usually using some kind of auditory
用一副聽覺
or visual Pavlovian response mechanism.
或視覺條件反射裝置
-"Audi-what-ey"? -And when it's over...
-聽覺什么  -事情結束后
What?
怎么
There's an after party?
有個慶功派對
Derek, get down!
戴力  趴下
You got to get to Maury Ballstein's computer.
你要拿到莫里·鮑爾斯坦的電腦
He recorded everything in case they ever turned on him.
他記錄了一切以防他們對付他
Derek, get a grip! Get a grip!
戴力  冷靜一點
Good luck to you, Derek. I've always been a fan of Blue Steel.
祝你好運  戴力  我一直是個藍鋼迷
And I hear Magnum is gonna blow us all away.
聽說炮火會很轟動
Come on !
來吧
-Get out of here. -Hang in there, J. P.
-快走  -在這等著  J.P.
You freakin' idiot!
你這個笨蛋
Man, that was close.
真驚險
I can't believe Maury's in on it, too.
我不能相信莫里也是同謀
That she-male Katinka's not messing around.
那個男人婆卡廷卡不是胡來的
You're telling me! For a second there,
你剛剛告訴我
I thought someone was gonna be reading our "eugoogoly."
我以為有人會讀我們的致悼遲
Okay, all right, we need a place to hide.
好吧  我們要躲起來
Derek, where's the last place anyone would ever expect to look for you?
戴力  有哪個地方不會有人去找你的
I don't know.
我不知道
Think, okay? This is important!
想想  好嗎  這很重要
I hate Hansel !
我很韓塞爾
Hansel, Hansel!
韓塞爾  韓塞爾
Everywhere I look! Hansel! Hansel, Hansel!
到處都看見韓塞爾  韓塞爾  韓塞爾
Were you looking for a rematch?
你要來重賽嗎
Excuse me, Hansel.
對不起  韓賽爾
I don't think there's an easy way to put this,
這是很難解釋的
so I am just gonna lay it out.
所以我來說吧
Derek has been brainwashed
戴力被人洗腦
to kill the prime minister of Malaysia.
要啥馬來西亞的總理
And?
那又如何
And we need a place to hide until we figure this whole thing out.
我們想找地方藏身直至想到辦法
Derek said this would probably be
戴力說這里
the last place anyone would look for him.
絕不會有人來找他
Yeah, you're cool to hide here.
你們可以躲在這里
But first, me and him got to straighten some shit out.
但我和他首先要弄清楚一件事
Fine.
好的
Why you been acting so messed up towards me?
為何你對我這么有敵意
Well, you go first.
你先說
I don't know. Maybe I felt a little threatened or something,
不知道  我或許感到有點受威脅
'cause your career is, kind of, just blossoming,
你的事業如日中天
and mine's, kind of, winding down or whatever.
我就走下坡
And I felt like, "This guy's really hurting me,"
我覺得這個人傷了我的心
and it hurt.
真的很受傷
And I felt like when you told me to Dere-lick my balls,
你說滾蛋時我很傷心
that really hurt.
非常傷心
Maybe I was scared, man. You're Derek Zoolander!
或者我害怕吧  你是戴力·祖蘭德
Yeah, you're Derek Zoolander.
是啊  你是戴力·祖蘭德
You know what it's like to be another model
你知道在你陰影下
and be in Derek Zoolander's shadow?
當男模是什么樣的嗎
You want to hear something crazy?
想聽點瘋狂的嗎
Your work
你在95年
in the winter '95 International Male catalogue
冬季國際男性目錄的表現
made me want to be a model.
讓我想當模特
I freakin' worship you, man.
我實在很崇拜你
l'm sorry l was whack.
抱歉我發瘋
I was whack.
我才是瘋的
So welcome to chez Hansel.
歡迎光臨韓宅
You're welcome to hide out here as long as you want.
你們在這里躲多久都行
Well, there isn't much time. The show's tomorrow night.
時間不多了  明晚就舉行表演
We have to figure out a plan by then.
我們要想出個計劃
I'll round up the troops here.
我會在這里召集部隊
Hey, what's up, y'all? This is Derek and Matilda.
怎么了  這是戴力和瑪蒂爾達
Derek, you know Natani and Chloe.
戴力  你認識娜塔妮和科洛吧
We got Buzzy Sullivan, big wave surfer from Maverick's.
有巴茲·沙利文  著名滑浪手
This is this fantastic band, the Little Kings,
我在芬蘭認識
I met when I was ice sailing in Finland.
這隊小皇帝樂隊
That's my Sherpa, Lapsang.
那是我的雪爾帕人  樂生
Okay, so, hey, everybody! Listen up for a second.
大家聽著
Derek and Matilda are in hiding 'cause some dudes brainwashed Derek,
戴力和瑪蒂爾達要躲起來因為戴力被洗腦
to off the prime minister of Micronesia.
要殺密克羅尼西亞總理
-Malaysia. -Right.
-馬來西亞  -對
So, they're gonna be hiding here for a little while.
他們要在這里躲一會
Let's show them a good time.
招呼他們
-Right on ! -All right, come on, over here.
-這兒  -好的  來吧  過來
Hey, Ennui, will you do me a favour?
安蕾  你能幫我個忙嗎
Will you get me some of that tea that me and Lapsang got,
你能幫我拿我和樂生
when we were free climbing the Mayan ruins?
爬馬雅族遺址時喝的茶給我嗎
This... This is really strong tea.
這種茶味道真的很濃
No, it's just right. Trust me.
不  濃淡很適中  相信我
What with all the intrigue you guys have been dealing with.
你們一直要應付這么多陰謀
You know, Matilda, I'm surprised you're so worried about "Der-rock."
瑪蒂爾達  你這么擔心戴力令我詫異
From that article that I read, it seems like
從我讀過的文章看來
you don't really care too much about guys in our line of work.
你漠視我們的同行
Why do you hate models, Matilda?
為何你討厭模特  瑪蒂爾達
-Honestly? -Yes.
-要聽實話  -是的
I think they're vain, stupid and incredibly self-centred.
我覺得他們虛榮  愚蠢和自負
I totally agree with you.
我完全同意
But how do you feel about male models?
但你對男模有何看法
Sweet.
可愛
No, no! Okay, but seriously, Matil. Is it all right if I call you Matil?
不  好吧  但說真的  瑪蒂  能叫你瑪蒂嗎
What's the deal, yo-yo?
是什么一回事
'Cause you're not telling us the whole story.
你沒有把實情告訴我們
There's something else, isn't there?
還有別情
You guys really want to know the truth?
你真的想知道
-Yeah. -Okay, then I'm gonna tell you the truth.
-是的  -好吧  我告訴你
When I was in seventh grade, I was the fat kid in my class.
我念七年級時是班里的胖子
All right, forget it.
算了吧
-No. -Dude, be cool tonight. Come on.
-不  -老友  冷靜點
I'm sorry. Please, go ahead. My mistake.
抱歉  請繼續說  我錯了
I was the one that all the pretty girls used to make fun of.
我是所有漂亮女孩捉弄的對象
It was an awkward phase.
那是個很難受的階段
Anyway,
總之
every day after school, I would come home and...
每天下課回家后
You know, I'd flip through the pages of my mom's Vogue and Glamour.
我會翻閱我媽的時裝雜志
And I just...
然后我就是...
I'd look at these women,
我看著那些女人
these perfect, beautiful,
完美  漂亮
just unbelievable, skinny women.
不可思議的窈窕女人
I just couldn't...
我只是不...
Oh, I couldn't understand why I didn't look like them.
我不明白為何我不像她們
I... I just didn't get it. So...
我真的不明白  所以...
So I became...
所以我變得...
What?
什么
Bulimic.
食欲過盛
You can read minds?
你可以看透思想
It's when you throw up after every meal.
是每頓飯后你都嘔吐
See, you know what? This is exactly what you models do to people.
這就是你們模特兒對人們的影響
You make them feel bad about themselves.
你令他們感到內疚
Matilda...
瑪蒂爾達...
Matilda, it's just...
瑪蒂爾達  這只是...
So what? I throw up after lots of meals.
那又如何  我飯后經常嘔吐
So do I. lt's a great way to lose pounds before a show.
我也是  這是表演前減磅的好方法
Are you guys insane? Do you understand that it's a disease.
你們瘋的嗎  可知道這是病態
Wow. How did that affect you with guys?
這些男人
Did they not want to get busy with you?
不想跟你混嗎
-Good point. -Okay. You know what?
-有道理  -好吧  你知道嗎
I'm not gonna sit here with both of you and discuss my sex life or...
我不要坐在這里討論我的性生活...
Or lack thereof.
或者缺乏性生活
You mean, like, like you, like you...
你是說...
-Haven't really... -You haven't...
-你有一段時間... -你沒有...
-Done it... -Done it in a while, yeah.
-沒做過了... -做有一段時間了  是的
Okay, what's a while? Like, eight days?
一段時間是多久  八天
More?
多點
Try a couple years.
猜猜兩年
Oh, snap!
天
How do you live? How do you live?
你怎么過活
Seriously. Do you service yourself ten times a day?
說真的  你每天自我服務十次嗎
-End of discussion ! -Easy. Okay, hold on.
-終止討論  -放松點  等一等
-Easy, easy. -I'm not comfortable talking,
-放松  放松  -我不想談
-Easy. Easy. -This is...
-放松  放松  -這是...
This has been an emotional day for all of us.
我們今天都很激動
I think we should get naked.
我看我們應該赤裸
What?
什么
Don't ask questions.
別問問題
Just give in to the power of the tea.
屈服在茶的威力之下
So I'm rappelling down Mount Vesuvius,
我走下維蘇威火山時
when suddenly I slip and I start to fall.
突然摔倒然后開始下墜
I mean, I'm about to die. Hot bread, Zeke.
我是說  我快死了  熱面包  錫基
Just falling. I'll never forget the terror.
只是下墜  我永遠不會忘記那種恐懼
When suddenly I remember, "Holy shit. Hansel,
我突然記起 "見鬼  韓塞爾
"haven't you been smoking peyote for six straight days?
你不是吸了佩奧特六天嗎
"And couldn't some of this, maybe, be in your mind?"
難道沒有影響你的腦袋嗎"
And?
后來怎樣
It was. I was totally fine.
我平安大吉
I've never even been to Mount Vesuvius.
我從來沒有去過維蘇威火山
Cool story, Hansel.
有趣的故事  韓塞爾
Thanks, Olaf.
謝謝  奧萊
Dude, how dope was last night?
老友  昨晚有多興奮
I mean, the soil room. Dirt was flying.
在泥房里  你什么也看不見
You couldn't see anything. It was like, who's that?
什么都看不見  就像  那是誰
-Who's this? -I think I'm falling for Matilda, Hansel.
-這是誰  -我覺得我愛上瑪蒂爾達了  韓塞爾
Dude, I wasn't gonna say anything,
我不想說的
but it was crazy energy flying back and forth between you guys.
但你們之間真的很有瘋狂的能量
It was like, look out!
就好像說  小心
There was a moment last night,
昨晚有一刻
when she was sandwiched between the two Finnish dwarves
她身處芬蘭侏儒
and the Maori tribesman...
和毛里族人中時
-Yeah. -...where I thought,
-沒錯  -那時我覺得
"Wow, I could really spend the rest of my life with this woman."
"我可以跟這個女人共度余生"
Really?
真的
What do you call that?
這叫什么
l think you call that love, D-Bone.
我想叫做愛情吧
So what time is it?
現在幾點
-Almost 5:00. -What?
-差不多五點  -什么
Hey, guys, that show is in three hours.
那個表演在三點舉行
Derek is dead unless we get that evidence. Do you guys...
除非我們找到證據否則戴力死定  你們...
Easy. How about a "Good afternoon, Derek and Hansel.
放松  不妨說聲"午安  戴力和韓塞爾
"Thanks for the freak fest last night"?
感謝昨晚的狂歡會"
-Hello? -Hello?
-喂  -喂
Hi, Katinka.
卡廷卡
No, I just had a really late party night last night.
不  昨晚我參加派對  玩得很晚
-Derek, hang up the phone now! -Where am I?
-戴力  現在趕緊掛了電話  -我在哪
-Look, I have to go! -Hang up!
-聽著  我得走了  -快掛了
But I'll see you at 7:00. Okay, bye.
七點見  好的  再見
Derek, I thought I told you to turn off your phone.
戴力  我跟你說過要關掉電話
Turn off my phone?
關掉我的電話
-Yeah. -Earth to Matilda.
-是的  -地球呼叫瑪蒂爾達
This phone is as much a part of me as...
電話是我的一部分  正如...
You know what? Can we just cut it out with all the "Earth to's", please?
能否別再說地球叫某某嗎
We're not actually saying this is the Earth calling you, Matilda.
我們不是說地球在找你
Yeah. No, I got that. I understand you don't literally mean...
我明白  我知道你不是真的...
No, I don't think you do.
我覺得你不明白
Listen. It's not like we think that we're actually in a control tower,
聽著  我們不是在控制塔里
trying to reach outer space aliens or something, okay?
嘗試聯絡外星人  明白嗎
Hello.
有人嗎
-Oh, snap! -A joke.
-天  -開玩笑的
Okay, you know what?
好吧  你知道嗎
Instead of doing that, I'm gonna try to figure out a way into Maury's,
在戴力行刺政要前想辦法
before Derek assassinates a world leader.
潛入莫里那里
Wait a minute.
等等
I might just have an idea.
我好像有個主意
They'll be looking for us at Maury's, right?
他們會去莫里那里找我們  對嗎
But they won't be looking for...
但他們不會找...
Not us.
不是我們
Derek, what are you talking about?
戴力  你在說什么
Hansel, do you have a cosmetics case?
韓塞爾  你有沒有化妝箱
Sure, I mean, just for touch-ups or whatever.
當然有  用來補妝
What are you gonna do with that?
你要這個干什么
That'll do. Early in my career,
這個行了  早些時候
I used to do my own makeup styling and tailoring.
我習慣親自化妝  造型和修改
If I can create a basic disguise for us,
如果我們化了妝
we may just be able to sneak into Maury's, undetected.
就能潛入去
You is talkin' loco and I like it.
你在胡說  我喜歡這樣
Welcome to Derelicte.
歡迎來到頹廢
Hansel calling Matil. Hansel calling Matil.
韓塞爾呼叫瑪蒂  韓塞爾呼叫瑪蒂
We have entry. Repeat.
我們進去了  重復
-We have entry. -Okay, guys. I hear you.
-我們進去了  -好的伙計們  我聽到了
Now, once you get the info, l want you to e-mail it to my office
你們拿到資料就電郵到我的公司
and I'll download the files,
我會下載檔案
we'll rendezvous and take the information to the police.
再把資料交給警方
We hear you loud and clear.
明白
Listen, Matil.
聽著  瑪蒂
l've been thinking a lot about that bulimia thing.
我思索過關于那暴食的事
And I want you to know I understand where you're coming from.
希望你知道我明白你過去的問題
I feel really bad that good-looking people like us,
我們這些樣子漂亮的人
made you throw up and feel bad about yourself.
令你嘔吐和內疚使我感到很難過
For serious.
真的
-Thanks, Derek. Now, hurry up. -Okay.
-謝謝  戴力  現在快點  -好的
Hey, I finally got the results
我終于查到了
on the name check you asked for on Jacobim Mugatu.
關于詹科拜·莫加圖這個名字的結果了
-Or should I say Jacob Moogberg. -What?
-或者我該叫雅各布·莫伯格  -什么
He changed his name when he went into the fashion business.
他進時裝界時改了名字
Apparently, the guy was the original guitar synth player,
原是弗蘭基去好萊塢樂隊
for that band Frankie Goes to Hollywood,
的吉他手
but he got kicked out, before they hit it big
他在《放松》流行前
with that song Relax.
已被踢走
After the Frankie folks gave him the heave-ho,
弗蘭基等人拋棄他之后
he held a series of odd jobs until,
他做過幾份工作直到
get this, he invented the piano-key necktie in 1985.
這個  在1985年發明了琴鍵領帶
The guy's been a fashion designer ever since.
他從此做了時裝設計師
First obstacle.
第一個障礙
You ever use one of these?
有沒有用過這個
I don't think so.
我想沒有
Watch out. Watch... Fix that hem, Jason.
小心  杰森  縫好裙腳
Please. I need... Katinka!
我需要...卡廷卡
He's not here yet, Jacobim.
他還未到  詹科拜
-That little toad-face better show. -He will show.
-那個笨蛋快點出現  -他回來的
Good, because I'm a hot little potato right now.
好的  因為我現在焦急死了
There must be an "on" button somewhere.
一定有個開關的
Did you press that apple thing?
你有按過那個蘋果嗎
Wait! Hansel !
等等  韓塞爾
Let's not lose our cool.
別沖動
Then we're no better than the machine.
我們比機器好不了多少
lt's almost 7:00. I got to go.
快七點了  我要走了
No! Derek. Der, wait.
不  等等
If you go, they'll make you kill that Eurasian dude.
他們會逼你殺那個歐亞佬的
I don't care, Hansel. I've never been late for a show in my life.
我不在乎  韓塞爾  我表演從來不遲到的
I don't plan on starting now.
現在也不會創先河
Damn it, you're right.
媽的  你說得對
Do me a favour.
幫我個忙
If anything happens to me, I want you to give this to Matilda.
如果我有不測  把這個交給瑪蒂爾達吧
-No. -Please, Hansel. Take it. Please.
-不  -求你了  韓塞爾  拿著
-Man. -Take it.
-老兄  -拿著
Let's just say I'll hold on to it till you get back.
這樣吧  我會拿著它直到你回來
Go! Go!
快走
We're live at the Derelicte show,
我們在頹廢匯演現場
where controversial designer Jacobim Mugatu,
富有爭議的設計師詹科拜·莫加圖
has extended the olive branch
把橄欖樹枝交給
to the Malaysian Prime Minister Hassan,
馬來西亞總理哈桑
making him the guest of honour at tonight's show.
使他成為大會的貴賓
And starring in that show, veteran supermodel Derek Zootander.
大會的主角是資深超模戴力·祖蘭德
Guys, what's happening? Did you find the files?
什么事  你們找到那些檔案嗎
Matilda, we've got problems.
瑪蒂爾達  我們有麻煩了
Derek's already left for the show.
戴力去了表演
No. No, he can't. We don't even know what the trigger is.
不能去  我們不知觸發語是什么
He just went running out of here. I couldn't stop him.
他剛走了  我阻止不到他
-I'll call him on his phone. -He doesn't have it.
-我打他的電話吧  -他沒有拿
-What? -Yeah, he doesn't have it.
-什么  -他沒有拿電話
What are you talking about? He always has it.
你在說什么  他總是帶著
-No, he gave it to me. -Did you find the files?
-他交了給我  -你找到檔案嗎
I don't even know what they... What do they look like?
我不知道他們...它們是怎樣的
They're in the computer.
它們在電腦里
They're in the computer?
在電腦里
Yeah, they're definitely in there. I just don't know how he labelled them.
是的  絕對在那里  我不知道他怎么歸類
-I got it. -You got to figure it out.
-拿到了  -你得想辦法
We're running out of time, Hansel,
我們沒時間了  韓塞爾
you got to find them and meet me at the show.
找到后去表演會場會合
Roger.
收到
In the computer.
在電腦里
It's so simple.
很簡單
Hey, I just cut up a couple of cantaloupe halves,
若你餓了
with some cottage cheese, if you're hungry.
就切兩片甜瓜加干酪
Not the right time. I need to figure out this trigger
還不到時間  我得再戴力動手
before Derek kills the Malaysian prime minister.
殺死馬來西亞總理之前想到觸發語
You just seem a little tense. I was trying to help you relax.
你看起來很緊張  我想幫你放松一下
Relax? The last thing I need to do right now is...
放松  我才不要...
-That's it. -Let's go, people!
-對了  -我們走
Let's go! Vagrants and whores, you're wanted in Makeup!
我們走  乞丐和妓女們  去化妝間
Runaways and street hustlers, you're next!
跟著是逃犯和街頭惡霸
-You had us worried, Derek. -Everything's cool.
-你擔心死我們了  -一切順利
-l'm really super psyched for the show. -Good.
-我準備好出場了  -好
Just remember, relax.
記著  放松
Two minutes, Derek.
兩分鐘  戴力
There he is.
他來了
I just want to wish you good luck.
我只想祝你好運
Don't you mean "Good-bye"?
你不是指再見嗎
What are you talking?
你說什么
I know it was you, Maury.
我知道是你  莫里
I know it was you,
我知道是你
and it breaks my heart.
這讓我很傷心
Derek, l don't know what you're talking.
戴力  我不知道你在說什么
Derek, I'm...
戴力  我...
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Glad you could join us, Kmart.
真幸運你能加入我們  凱馬特
Lucky for you, there is no dress code.
幸好你穿衣沒有準則
I am vile spew
我是貧苦大眾
of the wretched masses.
的穢物
I am really, really dirty.
我非常骯臟
I am Derelicte!
我是頹廢
You make me sick to my stomach, Jaco.
莫加  你令我惡心
It'll all be over soon.
這件事很快會結束
Derek Zoolander will be dead and you'll be fine.
戴力·祖蘭德會死掉  你就會沒事
You always are.
你總會沒事
Come on, Derek. You're on.
來吧戴力  到你了
Break a leg, Derek.
祝你好運  戴力
Derek...
戴力...
It's Relax!
是"放松"
I hate you.
我恨你
I'm fine. I've done this a thousand times.
我很好  我做過這個一千次了
The trigger! It's...
觸發語是...
Concentrate, Derelicte.
集中精神  頹廢
Do not be distracted by the beautiful celebrities.
不要被那些漂亮的名人分心
Celebrities.
名人
Do what you've been trained to do and kill the Malaysian prime minister!
照受訓指示殺死馬來西亞總理
Just do it already!
快點下手
D-Bone, I got your back!
我扶著你了
What?
什么
It's that damn Hansel !
是那個韓塞爾
He's so hot right now!
他現在很厲害
Popping and locking, fool !
出招吧  笨蛋
They're break-dance fighting.
他們在霹靂舞決戰
Derek Zoolander just tried to kill the prime minister of Malaysia.
戴力·祖蘭德剛才想殺馬來西亞總理
That's bullshit! Listen up, everyone.
胡說  大家聽著
Mugatu's a dick!
莫加圖是個混蛋
He tried to brainwash Derek to kill the Claymation dude.
他將戴力洗腦  謀殺那個馬拉佬
That's a lie! Zoolander snapped because he's over the hill !
說謊  祖蘭德發怒因為他正走下坡
He knew his career was over and he couldn't face it.
他知道事業完蛋了  他不能面對
No way, compadre.
不是的
We got 30 years of files right here in this computer!
電腦有你30年的檔案
They're gonna bring you down !
能令你倒臺
Oh, no.
不
Down !
倒臺
Where did all the files go?
那些檔案去了哪里
I'm taking you out!
我要干掉你
Yo, taste my pain, bitch !
試試我的厲害吧  婊子
Deal with that!
接招
You don't have the guts, Kmart!
你沒有膽量  寒酸鬼
Wanna bet? And by the way,
想打賭嗎  順便
you were wrong about my outfit.
你看錯我的衣服了
It's the Cheryl Ladd Collection, and I got it at J.C. Penney.
這是大公司的名牌貨
On sale.
大減價
Jig's up, Mugatu. Everything they're saying is true.
完蛋了  莫加圖  他們說的都是真的
I've been in on it for 30 years.
我參與這事30年
What are you doing, Ballstein?
你在干什么  鮑爾斯坦
I'm done, Jaco. I got a prostate the size of a honeydew,
我完蛋了  詹科  我的前列腺大得像白蘭瓜
and a head full of bad memories.
而且充滿糟糕的記憶
It's time to set things straight.
是時候弄清楚了
You have no evidence. Han-stupid destroyed everything.
你沒有證據  韓笨蛋摧毀了一切
I got two words for you, sugar, Zip disc.
我有四個字給你  保密磁碟
The whole thing is in my den in Long Island.
所有證據都在我長島的家中
I can have that evidence here in 20 minutes.
20分鐘內我可把證據送來這里
-That a boy, Maury. -Hold on a second.
太好了  莫里  -稍等
I'm afraid of the radiation.
我害怕輻射
Sheila, honey, it's me. Listen.
舒娜  親愛的  是我  聽著
I need you to bring that Zip disc in the den down to the fashion show.
我要你把房里那只磁碟拿來這里
I don't care what the traffic is like.
別理交通
Take the God damn service road and get off before the bridge.
拿上那該死的設備  上公路  在橋前下車
So put it in one of those Tupperware containers
把它放入塑膠盛器里
and I'll heat it up in the microwave when I get home.
我回來會用微波爐把它加熱
For Christ's sake, it's a casserole, Sheila! It'll stay!
看在耶穌的份上  那是砂鍋  舒娜  它不會壞的
Shut up!
閉嘴
Enough already, Ballstein !
夠了  鮑爾斯坦
Who cares about Derek Zoolander, anyway?
反正誰會在乎戴力·祖蘭德
The man has only one look, for Christ's sake!
他只有一個表情  看在耶穌的份上
Blue Steel, Ferrari, Le Tigre?
藍鋼  法拉利  老虎
They're the same face!
都是同一張臉
Doesn't anyone notice this? I feel like I'm taking crazy pills!
有人留意到嗎  我像吃了瘋人丸
I invented the piano-key necktie!
我發明了琴鍵領帶
I invented it!
我發明的
What have you done, Derek? Nothing !
戴力  你有什么  你什么都沒有
You've done nothing ! Nothing !
什么都沒有
And I will be a monkey's uncle if I have you ruin this for me!
若我讓你破壞我的好事就是傻瓜
Because if you can't get the job done, then I will !
你不能完成任務就由我來做
Die, you wage-hiking scum !
去死  你這個加薪混蛋
One look?
一個表情
One look? I don't think so!
一個表情  不是的
There it is!
就是它
Magnum !
炮火
Holy moly.
我的天
Yeah, baby! That's what I've been waiting for!
好樣的  我一直在等這東西
Dear God. lt's beautiful.
天  很漂亮
That's my kid. That's my son.
我的孩子  那是我的兒子
Derek!
戴力
l love that kid. Dumb as a stump, but I love him.
我愛那孩子  雖然蠢但我愛他
Derek, you did it! That was amazing !
戴力  你做到了  真了不起
I know. I turned left!
我知道  我轉左了
Yeah, that too. But, Derek,
是的  那也是  不過  戴力
you saved the prime minister of Malaysia!
你救了馬來西亞總理
Right. Cool.
是的  厲害
Thank you, Derek Zoolander, for saving my life.
謝謝  戴力·祖蘭德  你救了我一命
On behalf of world fashion
我是代表時裝界
You're welcome, Mr. Prime Rib of  Propecia
別客氣  總理先生
Hi, I'm former male supermodel Derek Zoolander.
我是前超級男模戴力·祖蘭德
And here at the Derek Zoolander Centre
這是戴力·祖蘭德
for Kids Who Can't Read Good,
兒童讀書中心
and Who Wanna Learn to Do Other Stuff Good, Too,
暨學習好東西中心
we teach students of all ages,
我們教導不同年齡的學生
everything they need to know to learn to be a professional model
去學習做一個專業模特
and a professional human being.
和一個專業的人類
Our diverse faculty includes business management teacher,
我們的師資包括商業管理導師
and former model agent Maury Ballstein.
和前任模特兒經理人莫里·鮑爾斯坦
The designer's got your nuts in a vice,
設計師給你一千萬
offering you ten million plus three percent,
和百分之三的
of every pair of underwear sold.
內褲銷售利潤
What are you gonna do?
你會怎么辦
Screw him ! Hold out for more!
叫他去死  要求多一點
That's what I'm talking about!
我說的就是這個了
So join now, because at the Derek Zoolander Centre for Kids
快加入戴力·祖蘭德兒童讀書中心
Who Can't Read Good and Wanna Learn to Do Other Stuff Good, Too,
暨學習好東西中心吧
we teach you that there's more to life,
我們教你人生
than just being really, really, really good-looking.
不單要樣貌非常  非常  非常漂亮
-Right, kids? -Right!
-對嗎  孩子們  -對
And cut!
停
-Looks great. I think we got it. -All right, Mitch. Thanks.
-很好  完成了  -好的  米奇  謝謝
-All right, everybody! That's a wrap! -Hey, Hansel.
-好  大家收工  -韓塞爾
Hey, D-Rock,
戴力
I'm gonna take these kids over to the George Washington Bridge,
我帶孩子們
give them a little lesson in base jumping.
去華盛頓橋跳傘
I'll catch you in the teacher's lounge later on?
稍后在教員室見吧
All right.
好的
All right, guys. Last one to the helicopter's a rotten egg. Let's go!
最后上直升機的是笨蛋  來吧
Hey, Matilda!
瑪蒂爾達
There's Daddy! Hi.
爸爸在那里
-How's Derek, Jr? -He's great.
-小戴力好嗎  -他好極了
Guess what. He made his first look today.
你猜怎么著  他今天做了第一個表情
Really?
真的嗎
You wanna show Daddy your look, Derek, Jr?
給爸爸看看你的表情好嗎
-Wanna hang out for story hour? -Great. Yeah. Let's go.
-想留下來聽故事嗎  -好  來吧
Hey, who wants to hear a story?
大伙兒  誰想聽故事